Geonmo Gu

☑ gmgu@theory.snu.ac.kr

• https://github.com/gmgu

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Deep Learning: At LG Electronics, I am developing an AI coding assistant using large language models (LLMs). I have successfully trained LLMs in the distributed settings, and have deployed LLMs to hundreds of users. Recently, I am conducting research on fast and accurate LLM inference. **Algorithm Engineering**: My primary research efforts have been devoted to developing fast algorithms. I developed fast algorithms for graph isomorphism, graph isomorphism query processing, and multiple pattern Cartesian tree matching during my Ph.D. studies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

LG Electronics Seoul, Korea

 $Senior\ Researcher$

Apr. 2022 - Present

Artificial Intelligence Lab

- o Aug. 2022 Present: Development of AI Coding Assistant using Large Language Model (LLM)
 - Conducting distributed training for LLMs with up to 15 billion parameters.
 - Preprocessing terabytes of source code data.
 - Developing a fast LLM inference server for up to 500 users.
- o Apr. 2022 Dec. 2022: Development of Coding Education Program Utilizing AI
 - Trained a language model with 100 million parameters for Python programming education.
 - Developed a web client that inputs prompt, prints AI-generated code, and executes Python code.
 - Created an inference server for up to 60 users.

Seoul National University

Seoul, Korea

Post-Doctoral Assistant

Jan. 2022 - Mar. 2022

Institute of Computer Technology

- o Jan. 2022 Mar. 2022: Algorithm Development for Graph Isomorphism Query Processing
 - Developed a fast graph isomorphism query processing algorithm that runs orders of magnitude faster than state-of-the-art algorithms.

NAVER Gyeonggi-do, Korea

Internship Oct. 2021

AI Dev2

- o Oct. 2021: Analyzing Conversion Tracking Data
 - Conducted exploratory data analysis on glad for advertisement data to find meaningful trends.
 - Handled hundred gigabytes of (raw) conversion tracking data.
 - Solved optimization problem of maximizing conversion rate using linear programming.

EDUCATION

Seoul National University

Seoul, Korea

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

Mar. 2014 - Aug. 2021

- o Thesis: Fast Graph Isomorphism using Pairwise Color Refinement and Efficient Backtracking
- o Advisor: Prof. Kunsoo Park
- o GPA: 3.99/4.3

Incheon National University

B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering

o GPA: 4.4/4.5 (summa cum laude)

Incheon, Korea

Mar. 2010 - Feb. 2014

PUBLICATIONS

Geonmo Gu, Yehyun Nam, Kunsoo Park, Zvi Galil, Giuseppe F. Italiano, and Wook-Shin Han. "Efficient Graph Isomorphism Query Processing using Degree Sequences and Color-Label Distributions." *IEEE International Conference on Data Engineering*, 2022.

Geonmo Gu, Yehyun Nam, Kunsoo Park, Zvi Galil, Giuseppe F. Italiano, and Wook-Shin Han. "Scalable Graph Isomorphism: Combining Pairwise Color Refinement and Backtracking via Compressed Candidate Space." *IEEE International Conference on Data Engineering*, 2021.

Siwoo Song, **Geonmo Gu**, Cheol Ryu, Simone Faro, Thierry Lecroq, and Kunsoo Park. "Fast Algorithms for Single and Multiple Pattern Cartesian Tree Matching." *Theoretical Computer Science*, 2020.

Geonmo Gu, Siwoo Song, Simone Faro, Thierry Lecroq, and Kunsoo Park. "Fast Multiple Pattern Cartesian Tree Matching." *International Conference and Workshop on Algorithms and Computation*, 2020.

Myoungji Han, Hyunjoon Kim, **Geonmo Gu**, Kunsoo Park, and Wook-Shin Han. "Efficient Subgraph Matching: Harmonizing Dynamic Programming, Adaptive Matching Order, and Failing Set Together." *ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data*, 2019.

Myoungji Han, Munseong Kang, Sukhyeun Cho, **Geonmo Gu**, Jeong Seop Sim, and Kunsoo Park. "Fast Multiple Order-Preserving Matching Algorithms." *International Workshop on Combinatorial Algorithms*, 2015.

Seongi Hong, **Geonmo Gu**, Hyunjoon Kim, Kunsoo Park. "Performance Comparison of Adaptive Matching Orders for the Subgraph Isomorphism Problem." *KIISE Transactions on Computing Practices*, 26.1:38-43. 2020.

Seongi Hong, **Geonmo Gu**, Hyunjoon Kim, Kunsoo Park. "Performance Comparison of Candidate-Size Ordering and Path-Size Ordering for Subgraph Isomorphism Problem." *Korea Computer Congress*, 2019

PROJECTS

Framework of Practical Algorithms for NP-hard Graph Problems
Funded by the Korea government (Ministry of Science and ICT)

Seoul National University
Apr. 2018 – Aug. 2021

- Algorithm development for fast subgraph isomorphism, graph isomorphism, and graph isomorphism query processing.
- o Open source contribution for practical graph algorithms (https://github.com/SNUCSE-CTA).

Algorithm Development for Scanner/Stage Path Generation Supported by JASTECH

Seoul National University

Jul. 2014 - Jun. 2017

- o Sophisticated algorithm that can synchronize Scanner and Stage.
- o Development of path simplification method based on chain stabbing (computational geometry).
- o Efficient path generation methods by solving the traveling salesman problem (NP-complete).

NIPA-PURDUE Capstone Program

Purdue University

Center for Robotic Innovation, Commercialization and Education

Jan. 2014 - Feb. 2014

o Robot programming (Robotis Bioloid) in collaboration with students of Purdue University.

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Reviewer of Information Processing Letters

ELSEVIER

Dec. 2020 - Sep. 2023

Seminar about Distributed Training Techniques for Large AI Models

LG Electronics
Jul. 2023

Invited talk at STARLAB Meeting Korea Computer Congress

Jun. 2023

Invited talk at 2023 TOPCIT Workshop

IITP

Mar. 2023

HONORS

The 14th Open SW Developer Contest

Ministry of Science and ICT

Nov. 2020

o Project Title: GI (Graph Isomorphism Algorithm)

o Source Code URL: https://github.com/SNUCSE-CTA/GI

The 2nd Test of Practical Competency in IT (TOPCIT)

Ministry of Science and ICT

Awarded a Silver Prize

Sep. 2013

The 1st Test of Practical Competency in IT (TOPCIT)

)

Ministry of Knowledge Economy

Awarded a Grand Prize

Awarded a Gold Prize

Oct. 2012

SKILLS

Competitive Programming.

o BAEKJOON: https://www.acmicpc.net/user/gmgu

Programming Languages. C/C++, Python, CUDA C++, Rust, C#, Java, Shell Script, LATEX

- o C++: https://github.com/gmgu/GI
- o CUDA C++: https://github.com/gmgu/study-cuda
- o Rust: https://github.com/gmgu/study-rust

Libraries. PyTorch, TensorFlow, Triton (OpenAI), Seaborn, Pandas, PySpark, HuggingFace Transformers, DeepSpeed, NVIDIA Triton, NVIDIA Faster Transformer, FastAPI, gtest

o Triton: https://github.com/gmgu/study-trident

Others. AWS (SageMaker, EC2, Lustre, S3)